KRISTA STARR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

■ kristaleighstarr@gmail.com
 kristastarr.github.io
 (903)814-4150
 Austin, TX

in kristastarr O kristastarr

SUMMARY

My motivation for becoming a developer stems from my experiences working with kids with disabilities. As a case manager for students with visual, cognitive, and physical impairments, I developed an interest in universal design and accessibility. I became fascinated with the way innovations in technology were able improve educational opportunities, medical treatment, and everyday quality of life for people with disabilities. As a full-stack developer, my goal is to deliver products that offer elegant design and robust functionality, without compromising accessibility.

PROJECTS

Rainforest Partnership

Sep 2017 - Current

rainforestpartnership.org

Website for global non-profit committed to saving the rainforests

Currently working on making updates to existing Wordpress site, including donate using PayPal feature, and creating Wordpress Divi theme templates for converting site content to new Wordpress site

WeAreHear Aug 2017 - Current

wearehear.herokuapp.com

Location-based music and memory sharing app

Created with Ruby, Rails, Postgres, HTML, CSS, Tachyons, Javascript, and JQuery;

Implemented Carrierwave gem, Cloudinary CDN, and Twilio API to enable users to send custom texts to friends

Recipe Box Aug 2017 - Aug 2017

recipebox-skippers.herokuapp.com

App that allows users to share, search for, and rate favorite recipes

Created with Ruby, Rails, Postgres, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, and JQuery;

Utilized Devise gem for user authentication; created NavBar; created nested form to allow users to add new recipes with multiple ingredients

EXPERIENCE

Dev Bootcamp, Full Stack Developer, Austin, TX

Apr 2017 - Aug 2017

- Completed 18-week intensive full stack development training program
- Engaged in pair programming and collaborative group projects
- · Participated in Engineering Empathy training sessions to enhance communication and empathy skills

State of TX HHSC Blind Children's Program, Case Manager, Austin, TX

Sep 2015 - Jun 2017

- Planned and implemented networking and training activities for 150+ children with disabilities and their family members
- Assessed childrens' needs for assistive technology, including screen readers and screen magnification, and provided training to children and family members on how to use software and devices
- Participated as team leader in quarterly statewide Coordinator's Meeting

Progressive, Licensed Insurance Agent, Austin, TX

Jan 2014 - Aug 2015

- •Advised customers about products offered and made recommendations to meet customer needs.
- Provided technical support to assist customers in navigating company website to review and sign policy documentation

State of TX DBS Blind Children's Program, Case Manager, Austin, TX

Aug 2008 - Jan 2014

- Managed large caseload of over 100 families by maintaining routine contact via face to face meeting, telephone, and email contact, in order to assess current needs.
- Participated in a work group to analyze and initiate changes to state agency policies and procedures.
- Presented in a statewide training to teach peers how to implement the changes in policy.

CERTIFICATIONS

Design Thinking, Interaction Design Foundation

Jul 2016

Conducting Usability Testing, Interaction Design Foundation

May 2016

User Experience, Interaction Design Foundation

May 2016

EDUCATION

Austin Community College

Non-Degree-Seeking: Studio Art, 2012; Courses completed: Art History I & II, Design I & II, Drawing I, Life Drawing I, Ceramics I, Painting I

University of North Texas

M.Ed. Counseling 2008 B.A. Psychology 2005

VOLUNTEERING

Capital IDEA Girls Who Code Club, Instructor

Sep 2017 - Current

Pearl Street Darkroom Co-Op, Art Show Coordinator

Aug 2009 - Current

Blanton Museum of Art, Member Services Volunteer

Aug 2011 - Dec 2013